If you like to find more about my services you can visit my website canineheadstart.com.
So we are going to be talking about flea prevention in this short video clip.
There are a number of products out there that you can use on your dog obviously one way to prevent fleas is not have you dog go out side but that is not really realistic.
So we are going to be talking about products that you can use to prevent fleas.
In the last of couple of years there has been a increase of different types of options out there that you can use.
I'm just going to talk about three of the ones that are most commonly used and seems to be more effective.
So there is something called sentinel and this is a monthly tablet and sentinel actually prevents not only fleas but heart worm as well and the come individually wrap packages.
The dogs typically like to eat them they are flavored so they chew them right up and what this does is it prevents the production of cottin so if a flea jumps on your dog bites your dog and ingest the blood meal then the blood meal would have the chemical ingredients of the sentinel when they lay there eggs they would not be able to produce cottin.
cottion is the excess scalp of a flea so it doesn't kill the fleas but it prevents them from infesting or reproducing in your home.
So that is one option. Another option is if you know your dog has fleas there is something called cap star and this is a product that is oral product.
It works right away and it will actually kill all of the fleas that are on the dog for the next 24 hours and it start working in about 30 minutes.
So if you taken your dog to a place or a friends house or to a training school and you believe that there are fleas there and your dog may have gotten fleas this is a great product to use when you are about to leave before you bring your dog to your home.
Again this is a oral preventive and this is also a oral preventive.
We are going to be talking about external flea prevention in the next video.